Guide to the Floyd R. Newman papers, 1893-1990.
Newman, Floyd R. papers, 1893-1990
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Floyd R. Newman papers, 1893-1990.
37-5-1619
Floyd R. (Floyd Roy) Newman, 1890-1990.
37.1 cubic ft.
Correspondence, photographs, passports, programs, menus, broadsides, clippings, pamphlets, newspapers, portraits, drawings, sports equipment, military artifacts, clothing, and other items.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes papers and artifacts related to Newman's Cornell activities, including his time as a trustee, to his military service, his extensive travels, and his business career.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Cornell University Class of 1912. Floyd Roy "Flood" Newman was born in Casnovia, Michigan in 1890 and grew up in Churchville, New York. In 1908, he entered Cornell University where he majored in chemistry and participated actively in athletics. In February 1912, he skated the length of Cayuga Lake. While at Cornell, Newman was a member of Bandhu Fraternity, which later became Phi Kappa Tau fraternity. Following his graduation, Newman went to Shanghai, China, as a Standard Oil Company trainee. There he joined the Shanghai Volunteer Corps and rose to the rank of first lieutenant. As an Army officer in World War I, Newman helped organize the distribution of petroleum supplies to the armed services in the United States and France. In 1925 he co-founded the Allied Oil Company, Inc. of Cleveland. He was co-owner and secretary-treasurer of the company until 1948 when it merged with the Ashland Oil and Refining Company. Newman was a former Cornell University Trustee and served as a Presidential Councillor. He gave Helen Newman Hall, Newman Lab and the F.R. Newman Arboretum to Cornell, and supported the University's geological sciences and athletic programs.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists of correspondence, photographs and passports; programs, menus, broadsides, clippings and pamphlets, including "Dedication of the F.R. Newman Military Collection," October 25, 1976, Barton Hall. Menus, programs, maps, pamphlets, Chinese banknotes, and 103 negatives (with contact prints) of scenes of China collected during his stay in Shanghai, China, from 1912 to 1916. Photographs of Bandhu Fraternity; material concerning the Class of 1912 25th Reunion, June 1937; correspondence and other materials concerning the Class of 1912 Fifty Year Memorial Fund, and Newman's role in the establishment of the Class of 1912 Professorship; correspondence between Newman and the Cornell University Treasurer's Office, 1950-1963; and correspondence and testimonials concerning Newman. Also, material concerning Newman's trip to Japan; a letter from Floyd Newman's son, John A. Newman (Cornell University Class of 1943), concerning Mario Garcia Menocal (Cornell University Class of 1888), Cuba's first popularly elected president, and his brother, Adolpho Jose Menocal (Cornell University Class of 1888). Speeches and program of the dedication of the F.R. Newman Arboretum at the Cornell Plantations, June 10, 1982. Also, a large collection of Cornell memorabilia, including the skates Newman used to skate the length of Cayuga Lake in 1912; football shoes and helmet; baseball shoes and gloves; a 1912 Cornell University banner, buttons and freshman beanie; several beer steins, tickets and postcards.
Also, a collection of World War I memorabilia including photographs, medals, helmets, French and German bayonets and German uniform items; and memorabilia and documents from the Shanghai Volunteer Corps.
"Recollections" by David C. Duncan, June 8, 1970; typescript talk by Newman at the Union Club in Cleveland, May 12, 1983; cassette of interview of Newman by David Dunlop and Anne Bland, February 28, 1986; and Communiqué, Summer 1987.
History of Allied Oil Company, Inc., prepared as case material for the Harvard Graduate School of Business Administration, 1954; materials for the dedication of the Newman addition to the Riga Free Library in Churchville, N.Y.; photocopies of Newman's index cards for Allied Oil Company; photographs of Newman's 99th birthday; and a photocopy of an article about John Newman's miniature village, 1932.
Eight Chinese paper decorative gods, and a head-dress, circa 1914. Also, Newman's personal briefcase, a drawing of himself, and a photographic portrait by Fabian Bachrach. Also, miscellanea including photographs, newspapers, portraits, drawings, souvenirs, and other items from China, Japan, and America.
Photos of Japan and China, 1912-13; Japanese wedding gown, shoes and fan, gift from Yugi Yamaguchi to Cornell University.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Newman, Floyd R., 1890-1990.; Bland, Anne.; Duncan, David C.; Dunlop, David.; Menocal, Adolpho Jose, 1867-1932.; Menocal, Mario García, 1866-1941.; Newman, John A.; Yamaguchi, Yugi.; Allied Oil Company.; Bandhu Fraternity (Cornell University); Cornell Plantations.; Cornell University--Alumni and alumnae.; Cornell University. Class of 1912.; Cornell University--Endowments.; Cornell University--Funds and scholarships.; F.R. Newman Arboretum (Cornell University); Phi Kappa Tau Fraternity (Cornell University); Shanghai (China: International Settlement). Volunteer Corps.
Subjects:
Arboretums.; College sports.; Educational fund raising.; World War, 1914-1918.; Voyages and travels.
Places:
Europe--Description and travel.; United States--Description and travel.; Japan--Description and travel.; China--Description and travel.; Shanghai (China)
Form and Genre Terms:
Broadsides.; Menus.; Passports.; Photographs.; Postcards.; Testimonials.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 45, 46, 49, 50, 53, 54, 56, 57 are restricted.
Link to the printed finding aid, containing some additional information. PDF file
PARTIAL INDEX
Cornell miscellaneous
Boxes 7-10, 32-36
FRN miscellaneous
Boxes 10-12, 36-44
Allied Oil Company (see also Box 42 for Ashland)
Boxes 12-13, 18, 29
FRN family (mother, father, uncles, aunts, etc.)
Boxes 13-15
Churchville, New York
Boxes 15-16
FRN travel
Boxes 16-28
Cornell personnel
Boxes 30-31
FRN friends
Box 31
FRN confidential (RESTRICTED)
Box 45
Helen Newman (partially RESTRICTED)
Box 46
FRN employees - Hemlock Hollow and 862
Boxes 47-48
Elizabeth Newman Wilds and family (RESTRICTED)
Box 49
John A. Newman and family (RESTRICTED)
Box 50
Hemlock Hollow - services
Boxes 51-52
FRN - financial (personal) (RESTRICTED)
Boxes 53-54, 56-57
FRN - medical
Box 55
Unsorted papers
Boxes 58-60
Slides: including Morocco-Madrid-London, 1965, 1959, 1963; 3D slides, various locations, 1956-1957; photographs of trips, 1952, 1958, 1962; photograph albums, video tapes, cassettes, tape recordings, Christmas cards, magazines, scrapbooks, post cards, misc.
Boxes 61-72
Correspondence, 1950s, 1980s
Box 73
Correspondence, 1940s
Box 74
Correspondence, 1920s-1930s
Box 75
Correspondence, 1908-1919
Box 76
CONTAINER LIST
- Cornell University, 1916 -1985
  - Correspondence, 1916 -1926 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Greater Cornell Fund Dinner, 1949 " (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Testimonial Dinner (List of Enclosures), 1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Testimonial Dinner, 1949 - Explanatory Letter, 1979, to Dr. Gould Colman" (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Testimonial Dinner, 1949, II: Letters from other Cornellians" (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Testimonial Dinner, 1949, III: Official (Cornell University)" (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Testimonial Dinner, 1949, IV: Letters from family members, selected close friends and selected former Allied Co., Inc. employees" (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Testimonial Dinner, 1949, V: Central National Bank of Cleveland" (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Testimonial Dinner, 1949, VI: The following various items are enclosed, all for the university archivist (list of contents enclosed) " (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: 1949, 1977, 1981 -1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "Objectives - Japan - 1955 " (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Cornell Plantations Arboretum - Dedication, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous: 1963, 1970, 1980, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "The Venephe Wilson Story," 1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "The Immigration Problem," n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "The Union Club, Cleveland, Ohio...," 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Cornell University, 1908 -1912
  - Examinations for State Scholarships in Cornell University, June 6, 1908 (xerox copy) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Freshman Handbook - to the Class of 1912 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Diary (looseleaf notebook pages), Sept. 28, 1908 to June 2, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Receipt for "Unaform", 1908 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ticket, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Tag-Tag Day, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ticket, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlet, Triangular Debate League, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ticket, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Program, Freshman Banquet, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Program, Formal Opening of the New Sage Chapel Organ, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Program, organ recital, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Program, track and baseball, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Concert program, Cornell and University of Pennsylvania, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlet, "How Cornell Does It" - reprint from The Boston Transcript, May 1911 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Dance Program, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlet, Crew Celebration, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Program First Annual Chemists' Feed, Feb. 24, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program, Junior Smoker, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ticket, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Receipt, senior tax, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program, Class Day, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program, Glee, Banjo and Mandolin Clubs, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ticket, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Invitation, Class Day, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program, The Cornell Masque, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program, Commencement, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Program, Senior Ball, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Parade Notice, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Parade Notice, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Tag, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Tag, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Study cards (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlet, "To What Extent Should College Training Confer Practical Efficiency Along Technical Lines?", by Louis M. Dennis, reprint March, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlet, "Cornell Student's Handbook", Christian Associations of Cornell University (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlet, Cornell University Department of Physical Training (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlet, similar to 3 above but different edition (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlet, Interscholastic and Intercollegiate Athletic Records, published by Gillette Safety Razor Co. (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Shanghai, China, 1912 -1915
  - Notes on China, c. 1912 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Passenger List, S. S. Chiyo, Nov. 15, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Menu, Dec. 1, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Ticket, ship meals, S. S. Yanaguchi Maru, Dec. 1912 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Menu, Palace Hotel, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Menu, Palace Hotel, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Menu, Palace Hotel, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Menu, Palace Hotel, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Menu, Palace Hotel, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Concert Program, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Invitation, Shanghai Volunteer Corps - Washington's Birthday Ball, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Article (photocopy) from The Sun re oil trade training with SOCONY, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Programme of the Celebrations in Honour of the Raising of the Volunteer Corps, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program, Spring Regatta, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Program, Negro Minstrelsy, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Indexed Pocket Map of Asia, Rand-McNally (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlet, Information for Travellers landing at Shanghai (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chinese bank notes from H.D. Hashagen (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Free-hand signs (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Dated Memorabilia ca. 1913 -1920
  - Program, Lyceum Theatre, ca. 1913 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Card, "To My Brother Over There" and Christmas card, ca. 1918 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - The Cornellian Council Quarterly, Sept. 1919 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Menu-Program, S.S. Rotterdam, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Menu-Program, S.S. Rotterdam 1919 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Menu-Program, S.S. Rotterdam, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Menu-Program, S.S. Rotterdam, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Concert Program, S.S. Rotterdam, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Menu-Program, S.S. Rotterdam, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- 25 Year Reunion, June 18-20, 1937
  - The On-to-Ithaca Gazette, May 25, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Reunion Guide, June 18-20, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Program, "Rusticana", 1937 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Article from Alumni News, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Postcard - Notation dated Sept. 27, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Dated memorabilia - 1948, 1952, 1955, 1967
  - Newspaper page, Cleveland News, Feb. 14, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - The On-to-Ithaca Gazette, Jan. 1952 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Alumni News page, June 1, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper page, Syracuse Post-Standard, June 12, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Alumni News, page and photocopy, Jan. 1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Airline ticket receipts, 1962 -1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Passports, 1958, 1962, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Monseigneur May 30, 1956 ", 4 photographs (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Memorabilia - undated
  - Brochure - "The Chateau Féodal of Montrichard" (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Newspaper clipping and copy, "The 'Guide' of T.J. VanAlstyne, '03" (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Poem, "Ryan's going to leave us people, ..." (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Calling card - Miss Gertrude Emilie Maule (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Programme - Follies Bergère (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Card - Soldier's Mail (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Cornell University Memorabilia
  - 2 freshman beanie buttons (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Freshman beanie (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Red and white ribbon (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Insignia (?) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Ticket, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Registration certificates (19), 1908 -1912 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Ticket tag - Vanderbuilt Cup-Race (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Professional card with notation (Star-Palace Laundry) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Card - "Report to Company B" (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cornell sticker (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Postcards (2), words and music of Alumni Song and Alma Mater (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Postcard - man and woman (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Athletics tickets and stubs (10), 1908 -1912 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - C.U. button (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Bandhu dance and banquet program, 1910 -1912 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Framed print, C.U. coed (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Framed print, C.U. coed (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Broadsides (2): "Slip swine into your dark and slimy holes ..." (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Broadside: "The time has come ye frightened Frosh ..." (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Posters (10): football players, Gibson Girls (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Poster: Teddy Roosevelt (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Pamphlet: "The Dedication of the F.R. Newman Military Collection", Colonel Wortham Museum, October 25, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Speech at "Presentation of the F.R. Newman Military Collection", Colonel Wortham Museum, October 25, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - "Events and Memorable Experiences by F.R. Newman and Articles from The Allied Private", 1943 (2) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Photographs (Box 2, Folder 18-22)
  - Verbatim Excerpts from Newman' s Diary (used in Newman exhibit), 1908, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Academic Certificates, 1904 (2), 1905 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Valedictory Address: "The Immigration Problem", 1907 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - State Scholarships in Cornell University - Notice of Appointment, 1908 (original and 4 copies) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Examinations for State Scholarships, 1908 (5) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Story of the Shanghai Volunteer Corps, Shanghai, China and Life in Shanghai, 1912 -1916 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - F.R. Newman Display Case: correspondence, blue prints, photos (2) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- F.R. Newman's Experiences in Shanghai and China, 1912 -1916
  - Overland Trip (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Trans-Pacific Trip, Including Hawaii (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Travel through Japan (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Shanghai, Dec. 10, 1912 through Feb. 12, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Travel through Tientsin, Peking, Chang-Sin, Tien Report on Previous Trip Shanghai, Mar. 23, 1913 through June 15, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Soochow, Hangchow, Wusih Japan (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Hangchow, Shaolingfu (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Chinkiang, Nanking (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Photos and negatives: Shanghai, China, Japan
  - China, Country outside Shanghai (Box 5, Folder 1-15)
  - Unlabeled (Box 5, Folder 16-27)
  - Japan, 1914 (Box 5, Folder 28-39)
  - 1. South of Shanghai (Box 5, Folder 40-54)
  - 2. Canals (Box 5, Folder 40-54)
  - Nanking (Box 5, Folder 55-58)
  - Shanghai, etc. (Box 5, Folder 59-96)
  - "My Choisest" for enlargement Mar. 11, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 97-102)
  - Unlabeled (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Broadside (poster) for Negro minstrel show put on in China by Shanghai Volunteer Company, Feb. 22-23, 1915 (3 1/2 ft. x 5 ft.)
  - Diploma: Churchville High School, N.Y., Jan. 26, 1907
  - Diploma: Cornell University, B.A., June 30, 1912
- Additional papers
  - Newman speech to the Cornell Club of Northeastern Ohio, at the Union Club, May 12, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Cassette tape: interview of Newman by David Dunlop and Anne Bland, August 28, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Communique, Summer 1987 - "F.R. Newman: A Tribute to a Legend" (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "Recollections" by David C. Duncan, June 8, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Plat maps of Churchville, Town of Riga, Monroe County, New York, 1902, 1924 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Cornell University
  - Helen Newman Hall, April 23, 1978: Presentation of trophy case; presentation of Japanese wedding cloak and display case; dedication of gifts from F. R. and Helen A. Newman; letters ( 1979 -1980 ) to and from Yuji Yamaguchi (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Dedication of Helen Newman Hall, June 14, 1963: correspondence - Robert A. Kidera, director University Relations re: program, luncheon, various, Mrs. Girard (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Cornell Daily Sun, May 22, 1963 Letter from Cornell, June 1963 "On-to-Ithaca Gazette," October 1963 Cornell class reunions, June 1963 Various clippings (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Dedication of Helen Newman Hall: invitations (dedication ceremony); program (dedication ceremony); lists #'s 1-4; room assignments, Mary Donlon Hall (list May 31, 1963; official luncheon, Statler Hall; family dinner, Statler Hall; FRN bulletin, June 3, 1963; campus maps (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Dedication of Helen Newman Hall: "Personal" invitations; acceptances; follow-up, particularly re: rooms, luncheon, dinner and general arrangements (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - Dedication of Helen Newman Hall: declinations (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Dedication of Helen Newman Hall: letters of congratulations and appreciation; FRN acknowledgements, etc. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Dedication of Helen Newman Hall: remarks (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Helen Newman Hall: revised brochure, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Seisen Shogakko (School), Kamakura Yukinoshita, Japan, June 18, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper articles, 1981 -1987 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper articles of particular interest to FRN (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Club of Akron (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - C.U. Board of Trustees Council, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Cornell Club of Northeastern Ohio dinner, Cleveland Ohio-Union Club, May 12, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Helen Newman Hall: magazine articles, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Helen Newman Hall: exhibits, 1974 -1989 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Helen Newman Hall bank, Mackesey, 1971 -1972 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Helen Newman Hall bank, Mackesey, Corson, Ramin, Lewis, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Helen Newman Hall bank, MacDowell (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - The Venephe Wilson story, Dec. 27, 1983 - Apr. 7, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - F. R. Newman Overlook dedication, Oct. 31, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - F. R. Newman Overlook planning, Mar. 14, 1986 - Sept. 22, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - F. R. Newman Overlook planning, Jan. 2, 1985 - Dec. 20, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Beebe Lake - 150th birthday (Box 7, Folder 26-27)
  - Floyd Newman Laboratory of Nuclear Studies, Apr. 8, 1980: Letter to Hans Bethe, Mar. 7, 1980; Letter to Bethe, Mar. 10, 1980; Raymond F. Howes's letter to FRN, Mar. 13, 1980; FRN letter to Howes, Mar. 24, 1980; pages 24-26 of the Bethe news story referred to (Box 7, Folder 28-29)
  - Floyd Newman Laboratory for Nuclear Studies: arrangements, correspondence, etc.; photographs and press clippings; extra photos, etc., Oct. 21-22, 1949 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - "The Joyful Freshmen," Percy Field, Cornell U. (FRN freshman year), Oct. 1908 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Biographical and factual information: Cornell Alumni News, Oct. 15, 1951 - installation exercises President Deane Waldo Malott, Sept. 19, 1951; address "The Cornell Tradition" Prof. Robert E. Cushman, Sept. 19 1951; Cornell Daily Sun Sept. 17, 1951 - biographical sketches: Presidents White, 1868-1885; Adams, 1885-1892; Schurman, 1892- 1920; Farrand, 1921 -1937; Day, 1937 -1949 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Cornell University - first 100 years - Charter Day (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Addresses, speeches and excerpts - Dr. Edmund E. Day (furnished by Willard I. Emerson, 1951 ) (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - 75 years at Cornell (Sun, Apr. 16, 1955 ) (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - C.U. Centennial, Oct. 8-10, 1964; dedication of Malott Hall; academic procession and convocation; Cornell 35, U. of P. 0 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - 150th Anniversary dinner given by the Trustees of Cornell University to commemorate the birth of Ezra Cornell, The Waldorf-Astoria, N.Y., Dec. 3, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - College of Engineering Centennial Convocation, Award, F. R. Newman; professorship, Fred H. Rhodes, Oct. 21-22, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - C.U. publications, 1968 (including Univ. of Illinois). Also, exchanged letters ( 1968 ): James E. Vermette, Executive Director, University of Illinois Alumni Association, Louis D. Liay, Associate Director; Steven Muller, V.P., G. Michael McHugh, Associate Director University Development; minutes of meeting, Ithaca, Oct. 25, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Robert T. Paine Oriental Art Collection, Apr.-June 1968 (Robert J. Smith) (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - David C. Duncan Professorship (Carl Sagan), 1974 -1976: David C. Duncan, President Dale R. Corson, Vice President Richard M. Ramin, Neal R. Stamp, Gordon W. Duncan (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
  - Carl Sagan - Pres. Corson (official) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - David C. Duncan, Gordon Duncan, Neal Stamp press releases, 1974 -1976 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - The Great Ice Follies of 1912 (Box 8, Folder 10-14)
  - Tower Club (C.U.), N.Y.C., Apr. 20, 1966; Presidential Councilors; Class of 1912 as of Sept. 6, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - C.U. campus illumination, John Watson, 1968 -1972 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Thomas F. Van Gilder c/o Marriott Hotel, Newport Beach, California, Nov. 1975 - (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Fred H. Rhodes Endowment Fund; Cornell Plantations (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Motor car routes, Cleveland to Ithaca - points of interest, Cornell Campus and vicinity (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Motor car routes, Mr. and Mrs. Victor W. Hoffman, July 1977; trip #2, July 1982 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Motor car routes (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Adrienne Wilds, Feb. 29, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Mrs. Anne McFadden, Aug. 11-15, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Mrs. Ruth Kasmark and Miss Ruth Robertson, Niagara Falls, Ontario, July 20, 1976, Ithaca, July 21-22, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Mrs. Lois Schmidt, Sept. 1974 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Oliver D. Diller, May 1-2, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Motor car routes (copies) (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Lynn Vavreck (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Dorothy K. Browne (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Douglas E. Brown (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Richard Hoffman (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Kimberly Hainge (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Katie St. Vincent (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Sally Henninger (Box 8, Folder 34)